A Finding Aid to the Jack Stewart Papers, 1926-2010, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Research Files on Graffiti, 1972-2010; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 2.8 Linear feet Boxes 5-7,11; 3.18 Gigabytes ER03-ER05
  A high percentage of the items are dated circa 1975-1988, the years when Stewart was a graudate student at New York University. Items continued to be added after his dissertation was completed. Material added after 2004 largely concerns posthumously published writings. On occasion, these files have been referred to and possibly cited as Jack Stewart's "Mass Transit Art Graffiti collection."
  Published posthumously, Graffiti Kings: New York Mass Transit Art in the 1970s by Jack Stewart was based on his dissertation. Of particular note are the interviews (on 30 sound cassettes, 3 sound tape reels, and in digital format), transcripts, lengthy lists of graffiti writers' names/"tags," and Profile of a Common Offender compiled by the New York City Police Department. Interviews consist mainly of graffiti writers looking at slides and identifying graffiti and their writers. Also found in an interview with an official of the New York City Transit Authority. Many of the recordings have transcripts. Some of the transcripts identify slides that were being viewed during the conversation. Other transcripts do not appear to have recordings associated with them in the collection. Some transcripts are handwritten, some are typewritten, and others are simply notes from conversations. Where transcripts have been identified as directly documenting recordings in the collection it is noted in the folder listing.
  Also among the research files on graffiti is a copy of the first known instance of graffiti appearing in advertising - a Volvo ad showing the car parked in front of a graffiti covered wall.
  Some files are grouped by subject or record type. Paper records are arranged alphabetically. Transcripts and interview recordings are arranged chronologically.
  - Advertisement, First Graffiti, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Auction, Guernsey's "Graffiti Art,", 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
  - Book, Graffiti Kings: New York Mass Transit Art in the 1970s by Jack Stewart, 2008-2010; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records, see ER03. (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Digital Photographs and Document, 2010-2011; Archival Resource Key; 0.635 Gigabytes 166 computer files (Folder ER03)
  - Book, Mass Transit Art by Jack 7/Jack Stewart, undated; 1974-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Business Cards, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Chronology, circa 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Clippings (1970s-2000s), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10-17)
  - Coloring Book, 1977-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - C-Prints List, undated; 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Exhibitions, Graffiti, Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
    - The Bronx Museum of the Arts, 1999-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Christo del Bramante, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Fondation Cartier pour l'art contemporain, 2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Groninger Museum, 1991-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
    - Various, undated, 1970s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
  - Experience Music Project, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Films, Graffiti - Speedy by Julien Daniel, 1979-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Kings of Broadway, a film by Chris Pape (1998), Digital Video Recording, 2010; Archival Resource Key; 1.57 Gigabytes One computer file (Folder ER04)
  - Films about Graffiti - Style Wars, circa 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Fotofolio, Inc., 2001-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Historical Background, Pre-historic-1970 (undated, 1940s-1980), Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 13-15)
  - Interview Transcripts, 1973-1985; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16-19)
  - Interviews with Graffiti Writers, Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
    - "Graffiti Tapes", undated; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound tape reels (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - "Meeting in studio with Tracy, Chi-Chi", undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette label reads "First side transfer from reel 2" (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - "Martinez Graffiti", 1973 December 20; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound cassettes 1 and 2 of 3; 3 not found; has transcript (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - "Lonnie (Phase 2), T-168, C.A.T., USE1", circa 1974; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette has transcript (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - "Jack in Studio with Graffiti Artists", a film (1974-circa 1986), Digital Video Recording, 2010; Archival Resource Key; 0.971 Gigabytes One computer file (Folder ER05)
    - "Lonnie", 1972; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - "Tracy, Chi-Chi, Cliff, Zest, Clyde, Pel in Studio", 1974 April 19; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette has transcript (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - "Chi-Chi and Tracy in my studio", 1974 July 1; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette; 1 Sound tape reel (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - "Tracy and Chi-Chi", 1974; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette label reads "Transfer from large reel???" (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - "Tracy, Chi-Chi, Cliff, Zest, Clyde in Studio", 1974; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - "Wanted Clubhouse, Woodyrest Ave.", 1974 May 11; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette has transcript Tape label reads "transferred from large reel" (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - "T-168 with Bill Clark, winter of 1974", Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette has transcript (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Interviews with Graffiti Writers, Archival Resource Key (Box 7)
    - "Tracy and Chi-Chi", 1976 April 17; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette has transcript (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - "EHP and Letters Riso", 1976 September 29; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - "Interview with Edward Silverfarb, Director, Public Information, NYC Transit Authority", 1978 July 10; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette has transcript (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - "Graffiti; JS, X Vandils..., Gary, Hispanic Savage Ones Brooklyn", 1980-1989; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - "Caine, Johnny, Wasp", 1981 November 4; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - "T-168, Billy 167, Wasp I, Daze in Studio, parts I and II", 1981 November 15; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - "1Z, Lee, Pink, Craine, Haze", 1981 November 16; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - "Graffiti Group, Pink, Vinny, T-168, Daze", 1981-12-02; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - "Meeting with Chris who writes Freedom, Coco 144, Stan", 1982 October 12; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette has transcript (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - "Meeting with Chris (Freedom)", 1982 November 2; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - "Wasp, Daze, Pink," and Tue (also writes Mitch), 1982 November 8; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette has transcript (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - "Tracy and Billy review book", 1983 February 15; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound cassettes has transcript (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - "T-168, Wasp, Mitch", 1983 September 5; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - "Taki '83", 1983 September 9; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette has transcript (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - "BLADE, Dolores (wife), and SEEN", 1983 December 5; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound cassettes has transcript (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - "Blade", 1984 March 3; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - "Bama (Amrl) and Wicked Gary (WG)", 1984 November 14; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette has transcript (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - "Bama and Michael", 1985 January 11; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette has transcript (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - "Tracy and Chi-Chi", 1985 January 15; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette has transcript (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Lectures, 1979-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Maps, New York City Subway, circa 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Museum of the City of New York Graffiti Collection, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Names/Tags of Graffiti Writers, "Tracy 6 - Hell" and Names on Lavatory Door at Stewart's Studio, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Names/Tags of Graffiti Writers, Lists, 1985 March 10-April 19; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 11-20)
  - New York City Police Department, "Profile of a Common Offender,", circa 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - New York City Transit Authority, undated; 1960s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Periodicals, undated, 1990s-2000s, Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 23-24)
  - Signatures of Graffiti Writers (photocopy), undated; 1970s-2000s; Archival Resource Key; Oversized material housed in Box 11 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Slide Lists, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Slides Loaned, 1981-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Oversized Signatures of Graffiti Writers from Box 7 Folder 25, circa 1972-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 11)
- Printed Material, circa 1945-2002; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 0.7 Linear feet Boxes 8, 11, OV 13
  The miscellaneous items are the catalog of a silent auction and lecture announcements. Posters are for events sponsored by Cooper Union's Art Department and exhibitions. The Ocean Grove Memorial Day Weekend Art Event was an annual affair organized by Stewart for more than a decade.
  Additional printed material is included among biographical materials (Series 1), writings and notes (Series 3), research files on graffiti (Series 4), and scrapbooks (Series 6).
  - Book of House Plans illustrated by Stewart, circa 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Clippings (undated, 1930s-2000s), Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1950s-2000s; Archival Resource Key; Oversized Clippings housed in Box 11 (Box 8, Folder 3-8)
  - Exhibition Advertisements, 1964-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, undated; 1950s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1960s-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 11-18)
  - Miscellaneous Items, undated; 1980s-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Newsletters, 1980s-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Ocean Grove Memorial Day Event, 1980s-1990s; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Posters, 1971-1973; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 22)
    Oversized Posters from Box 8, Folder 22 housed in OV 12
  - Press Releases, 1950s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Reproductions of Artwork by Stewart - Design and Plans, undated 1953-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 24)
    Oversized Reproductions of Artwork by Stewart - Designs and Plans housed in Box 11 and OV 13
  - Reproductions of Artwork by Stewart - Drawings, Miscellaneous Subjects, undated; (1970s-2000); Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Reproductions of Artwork by Stewart - School Catalogs and Advertisements, 1950s-1970s; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Oversized Printed Material, Clippings from Box 8, Folder 4, 1953-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 11)
  - Oversized Printed Material, Posters from Box 8, Folder 22, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 12)
  - Oversized Printed Material, Reproductions of Artwork by Stewart from Box 8, Folder 24, 1962-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 13)
- Scrapbooks, circa 1990-2003; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.2 Linear feet Box 8
  This series consists of two scrapbooks, both containing mixed materials. "Anatomy of a Commissioned Work" includes articles and notes about brain function, a price list for 1990 exhibition of Anodyne: The Brain Painting at The Broome Street Galley, and excerpts from Stewart's correspondence with Rodman Townsend that were included in the exhibition.
  - "Anatomy of a Commissioned Work: Anodyne: The Brain Painting,", circa 1990-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - "Jack Stewart Exhibition of Paintings and Drawings," The Broome Street Galley, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Artwork, 1946-2000; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 0.3 Linear feet Boxes 8, 11, OV 12
  This series consists of designs and plans, drawings, paintings, and an etching by Jack Stewart.
  - Designs and Plans - Murals, undated; 1954-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Designs and Plans - Student Work, Columbia University, circa 1951-circa 1953; Archival Resource Key; Oversized Artwork - Student Work housed in Box 11 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Designs and Plans - Tables and Mosaic Table Tops, 1953-1958; undated; Archival Resource Key; Oversized Designs and Plans - Tables and Mosaic Table Tops housed in Box 11, OV 12 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Designs and Plans - Terre Haute Plan and Unidentified Projects, undated; 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Drawings, 1946-2000; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Etching, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Paintings, 1953-2003; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Oversized Designs and Plans - Student Work from Box 8 Folder 30, circa 1951-circa 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 11)
  - Oversized Designs, Plans and Drawings - Tables and Mosaic Table Tops from Box 8, Folder 31, Archival Resource Key (Box 11)
  - Oversized Designs, Plans and Drawings - Tables and Mosaic Table Tops from Box 8 Folder 31, 1953-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 12)
- Sketchbooks, 1951-2004; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 1.3 Linear feet Boxes 8-9
  Sketchbooks (44 volumes) contain drawings and sketches in pencil and ink. Among the subjects are: travel sketches from Hong Kong, China, and Greece; heads and a portrait of Stewart's mother; 10th Annual Ocean Grove Memorial Day Art Event; and many studies of sheep made for the Cluett Mural commission. Two volumes include writings. Of particular interest are notes on Franz Kline's funeral, May 1962.
  Although numbered in several overlapping sequences, the sketchbooks are arranged chronologically. Additional sketches of Guilin, China are found among the artwork (Series 7).
  - Volume 1: "M-29", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Volume 2: "Sketches and 1 Poem ('Shells and Stones') 1951", Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Volume 3: "Sketches 1957 J.S. L-2", Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Volume 4: "Notes on Kline's funeral May 1962, Visit to Roman Bronze Art Foundry, Sketches of Polo Ponies at 92nd Street Armory Polo Games 1960. M-2", 1960-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Volune 5: "1962 M-3" with Sketches of Greece and Items in the Archaeological Museum Istanbul, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Volume 6: "Sketches 1963 J.S. L-3", Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Volume 7: Travel Sketches, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Volume 8: "Guilin, China 1987 L-5", Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Volume 9: "1987 Sketches. Hong Kong and Guilin, China Sept. 1987 M-G J.S. [illegible] #20 was done on the train to Albany looking out the widow at the Hudson River. Dwgs. 21-24 were done in Ocean Grove J.S.", Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Volume 10: "Book M-5 1st studies for Cluett mural. Sketch of O.G. [Ocean Grove] fishing pier. Dark sketches of trees. Sketch of Dover Cliffs", circa 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Volume11: "M-3 All Sheep J.S. 13 drawings of sheep at NYC Central Park Children's Zoo. Studies for Cluett Peaabody mural", 1988-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Volume 12: "Sheep Drawings '89 L-6 5 sheep heads", 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Volume 13: "10th Annual Ocean Grove Memorial Day Art Event L-14", circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Volume 14: "[illegible] sketch. Sketches for paintings using concave mirrors. Potala Palace. Notes on my development. 1991 M-10", Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Volume 15: "6-92 Brain Circus studies of mammals at Nat. Hist. Mus. - 5 old men under Big Tree M-11", 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Volume 16: "M-19 '92-'97", 1992-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 8-9)
  - Volume 17: "L-9 Circus [illegible] Aug. 1993", Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
  - Volume 18: "1994 M-13 contains MH #147 unfinished", Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Volume 19: "L-10 1994-1995", Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Volume 20: "O.G. [Ocean Grove] and aerial views on trip to Atl. Book #0, 1994-1995", Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Volume 21: "1995 Brooklyn Bot. Gardens. Marina in horse show. M-14", Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Volume 22: "M-27", 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Volume 23: "#2 1996", Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Volume 24: "1996 M-16", Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Volume 25: "Heads, O.G. [Ocean Grove], Lauren, 1996 Aug., 16 heads, Book #1", Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Volume 26: "1996; Subway Station, Surf at O.G. [Ocean Grove], Heads; 1997: Heads [illegible] Clouds in Atlanta, Book #3", 1996-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Volume 27: "96 3 heads", 2001; 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Volume 28: "Portrait of Mother, M-18 1996-1997", Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Volume 29: "#5 '96 6 heads", 1996-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Volume: 30 "1/27/97 McMurtry, Ossana at 97th St. Y; Atlanta 2/16/97, Ma's back of head, wink-incomplete Jan. and Feb.1997 #8", Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Volume 31: "M-17 7-13-97 1:30 p.m. NY-Cincinnati, Cin-Atlanta arr. 5:30 p.m.", 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Volume 32: "ATL 10/17 to 10/27/97, NYC: Met Opera, Barber Seville, Pushka and Remmy #6", 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Volume 33: "2 heads, #9", 1997-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Volume 34: "Basto 7/18/97, Belmont 5/16/98, Studies for BMT Proposal 5/00, M-20", 1997-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Volume 35: "April-May 1998, #10", 1998-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Volume 36: "98 and 2K, Book #17", 1998-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Volume 37: "#12", 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Volume 38: "10 heads, #13", 1999-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Volume 39: "#14", 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Volume 40: "#15", 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Volume 41: "#16", 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Volume 42: "#17", 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Volume 43: "Book #21", 2002-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Volume 44:"Book #22", 2003-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 37)
- Photographic Materials, circa 1950s-2010; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 0.4 Linear feet Boxes 10-11; 0.208 Gigabytes ER06-ER07
  Photographs, digital images, and 35-mm color slides are of Stewart and other individuals, his artwork, and miscellaneous subjects. The exhibition openings and installations documented are: Grippi-Waddell Gallery (1964); Blue Hill Cultural Center, Pearl River, NY (1986); and "Anodyne: The Brain Painting" at The Broome Street Gallery (1990) and New York Hall of Science (2003); and a retrospective exhibition at the Ogden Museum of Southern Art.
  Additional photographic materials are included among biographical materials (Series 1), writings and notes (Series 3), research files on graffiti (Series 4), and scrapbooks (Series 6).
  - At 9th Annual Memorial Day Art Event, Ocean Grove, NJ, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Jack Stewart at Work and with his Paintings and Murals, undated; circa 1950s-1990s; Archival Resource Key; Oversized material housed in Box 11 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Jack Stewart in Urbino, Italy, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Jack Stewart with Others, 1970s-1990s; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Artwork by Stewart - Mosaic Tables, circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Artwork by Stewart - Murals, undated; 1950s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Artwork by Stewart - Paintings, undated; 1950s-2010; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records, see ER06. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Digital Photographs, 2009-2010; Archival Resource Key; 0.167 Gigabytes 19 computer files (Folder ER06)
  - Exhibition Openings and Installations, 1960s-2010; undated; Archival Resource Key; Includes 4 videocassettes (VHS) and born-digital records, see ER07. (Box 10, Folder 8-10)
  - Exhibition at Ogden Museum of Southern Art (2010), Digital Document, Archival Resource Key; 0.04 Gigabytes One computer file (Folder ER07)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects - Architect's Rendering of a Hotel; Tree, circa 1960s; 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects - World Trade Center Devastation, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 12)